I had a small accident three months ago.
Now luckily nothing much happened to me
but my car is completely damaged.
You can see that
both the doors on the right side are badly damaged and
especially the front door on the right side has
something like a hole on it.  And in fact,
you can see that the tyre of my car was
completely damaged.
I am not telling you all this just like that.
Here, when all this situation happened,
I immediately called my insurance company
and explained the whole situation.
What happened after that was a bit shocking.
That is why I will tell you about my insurance claim experience today
in the video, but along with that I will
also specifically tell you which insurance you should take in 2025.
Let's now see
what happened after I called the insurance company.  So when I called him
and explained the whole situation,
he said that the
right door on the front side was badly damaged.  So
we do one thing that we will
replace it.  But the rear door on the
right side is still
in repair condition.  So we will repair it.
But we will not do anything about the tyres.
I was like okay, no problem,
here I just requested them to get the
car
repaired from the company authorized dealership only.  As soon as he said this,
he said that Sir, if you get this done then
you will have to pay GST and your GFC.
Alldo I have 100% cashless claim policy
but still they said this.  So
he said that if you get it done from our preferred
dealership then you will
not have to pay much.  You will just have to pay a small charge of
around ₹1200.  So I
said okay, you do as you are saying.
As soon as I dropped my car off
for repairs, I get a call from them two weeks later saying
that they haven't received the front and replacement
so we haven't done the rest of the repairs.
So I asked how long will it take?  So
he said that he cannot say anything for 2 months.
I was getting very angry after hearing all this.
But I
also tried to explain it to him properly.  But the seniors and
juniors were not bothered.
Then I thought that we should reach out to the senior management
team of the insurance company
through Lindin.  So I did that
and I
also slightly mentioned a little beef.  Now this opened the eyes of the company
but it did
not solve the real problem.  Now,
he didn't hear anything.  They
stuck to their word and after 2 months
they got my car repaired.  When I
went to pick up the car, the mechanic there
asked, "Sir, where did it get stuck
?"  You have very below average
insurance.  And I was very shocked to hear this.
Because I am a
person who keeps comparing the best insurances.
And this is my job
and if I can make this mistake then you
can imagine what can happen to normal customers.
After all this happened,
I sat down for full-on research and
today I will tell you three to four names which
you can consider so that you do not make the same mistake that I made.
You people might be wondering
what kind of bad insurance did I have that I had such a bad experience.
Now I will not defame him by taking his name directly.
But that
company has now been rejected from my list.
So I will not include it in my list.
And now I will also
tell you later
with which company I am going to finalize my insurance.
Let's talk about the basics now.  There are
broadly two types of insurance.
One is comprehensive and the other
is third party.  Third party means that
any damage caused by the third party will be
covered.  Rest of the damage to your own car or yourself will
not be covered here.  And
under comprehensive, damage to your own car will
also be covered and third party
damages will also be covered.  Now here mostly
you should take comprehensive insurance
because by taking it you will have peace of mind
and here it is a bit expensive
but you will definitely have peace of mind
because here it is covering everything.
Now obviously its premium will also be
a little higher.  Now you understand
that you should take comprehensive insurance.
So here
I will tell you one by one which add-ons you should take.
So the first add-on is
RTI i.e. Return to Invoice.  That is,
here if there is any major damage to your car
or your car gets stolen, the
insurance company will give you
whatever amount is there in the original invoice
and this mostly includes
ex-showroom price plus insurance
plus RC. If
you do not take the RTI add-on that I told you about, then in
case of major damage, you will get only the
insured declared value of the car.
If the car is not there, then that
insured declared value can be
95% of the ex-showroom, but if
your car is three to four years old, then the insured
declared value that is also mentioned here will be given to
you only at 60 to 65% because
of depreciation.
You
can see at the top of the screen how your car depreciates as it ages.  Now here,
if your car is 5 years old then its
value has already reduced by 50%.  But here
if you take RTI then you will
get the full original price of the car.  But let
me tell you that this cover is
available to you only for the first three years of the car.   The
next one to come head on is zero
depth cover.  Now this is also called bumper to bumper
and you get it for 5 years.
You must be aware that as soon as you
buy a car, its value starts depreciating.
For example, if you assume that
you have just bought a car worth Rs 10 lakh, then after 5 years
its value will depreciate by 50%.  That means
only 5 lakhs will remain.  Now let us
assume that after 5 years there is
some major damage to your car which
costs around ₹50,000, then without
zero dep cover the company will reimburse you only ₹25,000.
But if you have a zero
dep cover then you will get the full ₹00.
If you take zero dep cover here,
your annual premium will increase by 15 to 20%.
But if you can afford it you
should definitely take it.  Now the next add on
is consumables which includes
ball bearings, nuts and bolts, AC coolant,
grease etc. and mostly all these things are present inside the
engine of your car which is the front part.
But if it
ever comes to fruition, it
can add 50 to 20% to the overall experience.
So here its add on is
available very cheaply between Rs 500 to 600.
That's why I am recommending this ad to you.
Now
I have told you all the important add-ons which were necessary.
But apart from this, many more ads also come.
Such as engine products, tire covers, key
and lock set replacements.  So
you can take all these also.  But it depends on you whether
you want to take it or not.  Like
in my case, my entire tire was blown out.
So I suffered an additional loss of Rs 5000.
But if you feel that any of these three
things are missing, you feel
that I should have an add-on for it, then
you can buy it separately.  Now
before looking at the best insurance companies, let me
recap once.  First of all you have to
take comprehensive insurance.   Do
n't take third party.  After that you must have
three advances.  The
first one is Return to Invoice.  Second is zero dep
cover or zero depreciation cover and third
as I told you is of consumables.
After that, if you wish, you
can go and buy engine protector, tyre cover or the other aids that I told you about.  So let us now see
which are the best insurance companies in 2025 and
here for this we will
look at the claim settlement ratio of all the companies and
look at the network garages.  Here
with the help of Flutter I am removing those companies
whose network garages are less than 4000.
Because if there is no network garage nearby then there is a
big problem.  You have already
seen my experience.  And by the way, the
company with which I was insured and
because of which all this happened is also in this list, so
that too is going to be removed from this filter,
so you can guess and
tell me in the comments which company
is that?  After applying this filter,
only 10 companies are left with me, so
we check the ICR i.e. Incident Claim
Ratio of these 10 companies.  But
before looking at the Incred Claim Ratio, it is
very important to know what the Incred Claim Ratio means.
This means
how much money the insurance company has paid in claims compared
to how much
premium it has collected in that financial
year.  That is, if the
incurred claim ratio of a company is 88%, then it means that
the insurer has made a claim payment of ₹88
for every ₹100 premium collected.  Now
what happens with ICR is that the financial health of a company gets
known.  For example,
if the ICR of a company
is more than 100, it means that the company
is paying more claims and it is possible that
in the future that company may go into loss
and if the ICR of a company is less than 70%,
it means that the company is rejecting claims for its profits
or is
charging higher premium.  So ideally
if the ICR of a company is between 70 to 100
then we should go with that company.
Now, just for your information, let me tell you
that we are going to look at the data of the last two years to
check all this.  The
ICR of almost all the companies is
in the Desire range.  But if the
ICR of any company is below 70 in any one year, then
we have removed that company from here.
And in such a situation, we are left with
only six companies.  Actually, it will be
very difficult to suggest any one policy to you
because everyone's needs are different.
But let me tell you my top four picks among these.  It
is very difficult to choose one here.
But let me tell you my four
top picks here.  Like HDFCO
, ICICI LBRD, SBI and Tata AIG, now out of
these I am moving ahead with ICICI LBRD,
so going forward my
car insurance will remain with ICICI.
So in the upcoming videos, I will keep
sharing my experience with them.  So if you like this video
then don't forget to write in the comment.
This is the best video on car
insurance so that all the hard work we are
doing for you will be successful.